Santa Clara, CA 95054 cesarkylecasil@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ckcasil github.com/ccasil cesarkylecasil.pink

Summary

I am a Computer Science major practicing full stack development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) I have experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. My primary goal is to contribute my passion for programming towards a company's vision while expanding on my technical skills.

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

• Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, Python, C, L⁴TEX
Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response

Database: SQL (MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js,

Django ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks and Libraries: Development Tools:

Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

(EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Miscellaneous: Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures,

Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model View

Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

Experience

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Jan 2018–Present

- Building Full-Stack, modern, responsive web applications for clients while providing quick feedback and support
- Managed a small team to work with clients to create websites for various needs

MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Programmed Garcons Android application using Android Studio and Java during early stages
- Rewrote the UI layout as well as updated deprecated code

Projects

Love Changing the World, INC.

Jun 2018–Oct 2018

Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding.

• Technologies Used: React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API, Bootstrap

Gym Log

Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

Dojo Attendance Tracker

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

Baskin Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.

• Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)